Finding Aid for the Morton Feldman Images by Jan Williams, 1974-1979
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Morton Feldman Images by Jan Williams, 1974-1979
Mus. Arc. 2.3
Williams, Jan, 1939-
1 box (56 35 mm. slides, 56 color 8 x 10 in. prints)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The Morton Feldman Images by Jan Williams date from concert tours made by Morton Feldman and the University at Buffalo's Creative Associates in 1974, 1977, and 1979.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
The collection of 56 slides was received as a gift from Jan Williams in 2001. The 8 x 10 color prints were made from the slides in 2001. Scans were made from the color prints by Library staff in January 2002.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
Collection contents have been digitized and are available in University Libraries Digital Collections.
Biographical Note
Jan Williams was born in Utica, New York in 1939. He earned his B.M. and M.M. degrees as a percussionist at Manhattan School of Music where he studied with Paul Price. Jan Williams came to Buffalo as a Creative Associate at the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts in 1964. He became a member of the University at Buffalo Music Faculty in 1967 and Co-Director of the Center in 1974. He has been a mainstay of the contemporary music scene, not only in Buffalo, but also internationally, as percussionist, conductor, administrator, and educator.
Composer Morton Feldman (1926-1987) joined the University at Buffalo Music Faculty in 1972. He was the Slee Professor, 1972-1973, Edgar Varèse Professor, 1975-1987, and the Director of the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts, 1976-1980. Feldman also established the June in Buffalo festival in 1975 at the University. Under his leadership the new festival was presented 1975-1978, and again in 1980, with a year off in 1979 when Feldman was on sabbatical.
Scope and Content Note
The collection of Morton Feldman Images by Jan Williams contains 56 slides taken during concert tours made by Feldman and Williams in 1974, 1977, and 1979. The tours were part of the activities of the Creative Associates and the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts at the University at Buffalo, The State University of New York. Locations of the images include Paris, London, Edinburgh, Lisbon, Barcelona, Perugia, Karlsrühe, Dartington and Harrogate, England, Hilversum, Shiraz, Iran, Padua, and Venice. Other musicians in the images include Lejaren Hiller, Eberhard Blum, Martha Herr Hanneman, Nils Vigeland, Dennis Kahle, David Gibson, Julius Eastman, Ralph Jones, Peter Gena, Jan Williams, Benjamin Hudson, Bunita Marcus, and Renée Levine, director of the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by material type into two series:
I. Prints
II. Slides
Container List
- Prints, 1974-1979, I.
  The description below also applies to the slide collection, except for the physical description.
  - Morton Feldman with David Gibson, July 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 01)
  - Morton Feldman in Paris shop, July 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 02)
  - Morton Feldman with Eberhard Blum and David Gibson, Feb. 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 03)
  - Morton Feldman with Eberhard Blum and Dennis Kahle (partial), Feb. 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 04)
  - Morton Feldman with Dennis Kahle, Feb. 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 05)
  - Eberhard Blum and Renée Levine; Royal Festival Hall in background, Feb. 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 06)
  - Morton Feldman with Eberhard Blum, Jan Williams, Renée Levine, and Dennis Kahle; Royal Festival Hall in background, Feb. 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 07)
  - Morton Feldman with Julius Eastman, Ralph Jones, and Peter Gena, Feb. 13, 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 08)
  - Morton Feldman with Ralph Jones, Feb. 13, 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 09)
  - Morton Feldman with David Gibson, Feb. 13, 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 10)
  - Benjamin Hudson (violin), Ralph Jones (in doorway), Eberhard Blum (flute), Julius Eastman (piano), and Amrom Chodos (clarinet), Feb. 14, 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 11)
  - Ralph Jones, Benjamin Hudson, Julius Eastman, and Eberhard Blum, Feb. 14, 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 12)
  - Morton Feldman with David Gibson and Dennis Kahle, Feb. 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 13)
  - Morton Feldman with Dennis Kahle, Feb. 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 14)
  - Morton Feldman with Jan Williams and Dennis Kahle, Feb. 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 15)
  - Morton Feldman with Lejaren Hiller, Feb. 21 or 22, 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 16)
  - Morton Feldman, Feb. 24, 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 17)
  - Morton Feldman with Peter Gena, Feb. 24, 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 18)
  - Morton Feldman at piano, Feb. 24, 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 19)
  - Morton Feldman at kiosk, March 1, 2 or 3, 1974, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 20)
  - Morton Feldman with cows, July or August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 21)
  - Morton Feldman with Eberhard Blum, July or August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 22)
  - Morton Feldman with Eberhard Blum, Nils Vigeland, and Martha Herr Hanneman, July or August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 23)
  - Martha Herr Hanneman, July or August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 24)
  - Morton Feldman crossing a fence, July or August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 25)
  - Morton Feldman with Eberhard Blum, Nils Vigeland, and Martha Herr Hanneman, July or August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Morton Feldman with Eberhard Blum, Nils Vigeland, and Martha Herr Hanneman, July or August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 27)
  - Morton Feldman with Nils Vigeland, July or August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 28)
  - Morton Feldman, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 29)
  - Morton Feldman with Nils Vigeland, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 30)
  - Morton Feldman with Nils Vigeland, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 31)
  - Morton Feldman at Valley Gardens, Harrogate, Yorkshire, England, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 32)
  - Morton Feldman with Martha Herr Hanneman and Eberhard Blum, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 33)
  - Morton Feldman in front of shop window, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 34)
  - Morton Feldman, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 35)
  - Morton Feldman with Martha Herr Hanneman and Eberhard Blum, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 36)
  - Morton Feldman at piano, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 37)
  - Morton Feldman crossing street, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 38)
  - Morton Feldman with percussion set-up for performance of his King of Denmark, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 39)
  - Morton Feldman with percussion set-up for performance of his King of Denmark, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 40)
  - Morton Feldman with Eberhard Blum in swimming pool, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 41)
  - Morton Feldman with Eberhard Blum in swimming pool, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 42)
  - Morton Feldman in swimming pool, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 43)
  - Morton Feldman with gong, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 44)
  - Morton Feldman in front of Persian monument, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 45)
  - Morton Feldman in front of Persian monument, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 46)
  - Morton Feldman examining Persian frieze, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 47)
  - Morton Feldman with Eberhard Blum, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 48)
  - Morton Feldman on outdoor stage, August 1977, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 49)
  - Morton Feldman with Filippo Juvarra going to Cappella degli Scrovegni, May 1979, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 50)
  - Morton Feldman with Filippo Juvarra, May 1979, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 51)
  - Morton Feldman with Eberhard Blum and Filippo Juvarra, May 1979, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 52)
  - Morton Feldman with Eberhard Blum and Filippo Juvarra, May 1979, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 53)
  - Morton Feldman at restaurant table, May 1979, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 54)
  - Morton Feldman with Eberhard Blum and Bunita Marcus, 1979, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 55)
  - Morton Feldman at rehearsal at unknown location, 1979, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 56)
- Slides, 1974-1979, II.
  The description of the prints above also applies to the slide collection, except for the physical description.
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Musicians--Photographs; Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987--Photographs
Genres
Photographs; Color prints (photographs); Slides; Color slides
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Morton Feldman Papers, 1950-1999,
Mus. Arc. 2.1
Box 15 in this collection contains 46 photographic prints, all of which are available online as the Morton Feldman Photographs, 1939-1987, in
UB Libraries Digital Collections
.